[
  {
    "question": "गोपाल वंशको पहिलो राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["भुक्तमान", "यक्ष गुप्त", "निमिष", "रुद्रसेन"],
    "answer": "भुक्तमान"
  },
  {
    "question": "गोपाल वंशको अन्तिम राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["यक्ष गुप्त", "भूमि वर्मा", "जिष्णु गुप्त", "रत्न सेन"],
    "answer": "यक्ष गुप्त"
  },
  {
    "question": "महिषपाल वंशको पहिलो राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["वरसिंह", "भूवन सिंह", "यलम्बर", "नागराज"],
    "answer": "वरसिंह"
  },
  {
    "question": "महिषपाल वंशको अन्तिम राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["भूवन सिंह", "वरसिंह", "गस्ती", "रत्न मल्ल"],
    "answer": "भूवन सिंह"
  },
  {
    "question": "किराँत वंशको पहिलो राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["यलम्बर", "गस्ती", "जयदेव प्रथम", "रुद्रसेन"],
    "answer": "यलम्बर"
  },
  {
    "question": "किराँत वंशको अन्तिम राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["गस्ती", "यलम्बर", "भुक्तमान", "पृथ्वीपाल सेन"],
    "answer": "गस्ती"
  },
  {
    "question": "सोम वंशको पहिलो राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["निमिष", "भूमी वर्मा", "यक्ष गुप्त", "रत्न सेन"],
    "answer": "निमिष"
  },
  {
    "question": "सोम वंशको अन्तिम राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["भूमी वर्मा", "निमिष", "जिष्णु गुप्त", "वरसिंह"],
    "answer": "भूमी वर्मा"
  },
  {
    "question": "गुप्त वंशको पहिलो राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["भूमी गुप्त", "जिष्णु गुप्त", "यक्ष गुप्त", "निमिष"],
    "answer": "भूमी गुप्त"
  },
  {
    "question": "गुप्त वंशको अन्तिम राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["जिष्णु गुप्त", "भूमी गुप्त", "रत्न सेन", "नागराज"],
    "answer": "जिष्णु गुप्त"
  },
  {
    "question": "लिच्छवि वंशको पहिलो राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["जयदेव प्रथम", "जयकामदेव", "मानदेव", "अरिदेव"],
    "answer": "जयदेव प्रथम"
  },
  {
    "question": "लिच्छवि वंशको अन्तिम राजा को हुन्?",
    "options": ["जयकामदेव", "जयदेव प्रथम", "भूमी वर्मा", "यक्ष मल्ल"],
    "answer": "जयकामदेव"
  }
]
